Lillian J. Bragdon Papers 1998.0168
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Lillian J. Bragdon Papers
1941-1962
1998.0168
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.25 Linear feet
The collection consists of books, cards and letters from author and editor, Lillian J. Bragdon.
Bragdon, Lillian J.
Bibliography
Author: Tell me the time, please ( Lippincott, 1936). Words on wings: the story of communication ( Farrar and Rinehart, Inc., 1938). The land of Joan of Arc (Frederick A. Stokes Co., 1939). The land of William Tell (Lippincott, 1953). Color guide to home decoration (Sterling Pub., 1956). Let there be light (Lippincott, 1959). The land and people of France (Lippincott, 1960). The land and people of Switzerland (Lippincott, 1961). It’s fun to speak French (Abingdon Press, 1962). Meet the remarkable Adams family (Atheneum, 1967). Switzerland and her people (Lutterworth Press, 1962). Co-Author: Best in Children’s books, vol. 29 (Nelson Doubleday, 1960). Chapman, Frederick T., Luther Burbank (Abingdon Press, 1959). Shenton, Edward, Abraham Lincoln, courageous leader (Abingdon Press, 1960).
Biography
Lillian J. Bragdon was a children's book author and editor. Ms. Bragdon authored numerous books of juvenile non-fiction including The land and people of Switzerland, The land and people of France, The land of Joan of Arc, and The land of William Tell.
Custodial History
The Northeast Children's Literature Collection obtained Bragdon's materials through a donation by her daughter, Elizabeth Easton, in 1998.
Arrangement
Series I: Manuscripts (1956) Series II: Correspondence (1941-1968) Series III: Articles (undated, 1945) Series IV: Photographs (1928) Series V: Journals (1945-1947)
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detained information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the books and correspondence from Lillian J. Bragdon's career as a children's author and editor. In addition to English and Arabic copies of her 1962 book Switzerland and Her People, the collection also includes copies of It's Fun to Speak French and Luther Burbank, Nature's Helper. These are the only titles by Bragdon in the collection. In addition to Bragdon's own works, the collection contains correspondence with other authors, illustrators and editors, including Henry Beston, Warren Chappell, Roger and Lou Duvoisin, Alfred A. Knopf, Fritz Kredel, and Rudolph Ruzicka.
Separated Materials
Barnes, A. S., The Child's song book. Coordinating Council for French Relief Societies, Inc., Le Merveilleux de voyage de la goutte de vitamine. Dwiggins, W. A., Brother Jeromy. Fish, Helen Dean, Children's almanac of books and holidays. Lear, Edward, Nonsense songs. Moore, Anne Carroll, My roads to childhood. Pauli, Hertah, The Legend of the blessed tree. Yates, Elizabeth, One writers' way. by Lillian J. Bragdon: -- Luther Burbank: Nature's helper. -- It's fun to speak French. -- Switzerland and her people. -- Switzerland and her people (Arabic version).
Author.; Children's literature; Children's literature, American--20th century.; Editor.; Northeast Children's Literature Collection.
- Series I: Manuscripts, undated, 1956
  - Manuscripts (3 items), undated, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated, 1941-1968
  - Letters to Lillian J. Bragdon (12 items), undated, 1941-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III: Articles, undated, 1945
  - Articles relating to children's books, undated, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1928
  - Photograph of Hugh Lofting, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series V: Publications, undated, 1945-1947
  - The Bean Home news, farm edition (v.1:no.1), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Borzoi Books for Young People, Borzoi Battledore, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)